-DOCSTART- O
Hiroshima B-GPE
is O
the O
captial O
of O
Hiroshima B-GPE
Prefecture I-GPE
in O
Japan B-GPE
. O

As O
of O
June B-Date
1, I-Date
2019 I-Date
, O
the O
city O
had O
an O
estimiated O
population O
of O
1,199,391 B-CARDINAL
. O

The O
gross O
domestic O
product O
in O
Greater O
Hiroshima B-GPE
was O
US$61.3 B-MONEY
billion I-MONEY
as O
of O
2010 B-DATE
. O

Hiroshima B-GPE
was O
founded O
in O
1598 B-DATE
as O
a O
castle O
town O
on O
the O
Ota B-LOC
River I-LOC
delta I-LOC
. O

Following O
the O
Meiji B-EVENT
Restoration I-EVENT
in O
1868 B-DATE
, O
Hiroshima B-GPE
rapidly O
transformed O
into O
a O
major O
urban O
center O
and O
industrial O
hub O
. O

In O
1889 B-DATE
, O
Hiroshima B-GPE
officially O
gained O
city O
status O
. O

The O
city O
was O
a O
center O
of O
military O
activities O
during B-DATE
the B-DATE
imperial B-DATE
era B-DATE
, O
playing O
significant
roles O
such O
as O
in O
the O
First B-ORDINAL
Sino-Japanese B-EVENT
War I-EVENT
,
the O
Russo-Japanese B-EVENT
War B-EVENT
, O
and O
the O
two B-CARDINAL
world B-EVENT
wars I-EVENT
. O

Hiroshima B-GPE
was O
the O
first B-ORDINAL
city O
targeted O
by O
nuclear O
weapon O
from O
bomb O
bays O
of O
B-29 B-PRODUCT
in O
World B-EVENT
War I-EVENT
II I-EVENT
. O

This O
occurred O
on O
August B-TIME
6, I-TIME
1945 I-TIME
at I-TIME
8:15 I-TIME
a.m. I-TIME
, O
when O
the O
United B-ORG 
States I-ORG
Army I-ORG
Air I-ORG
Forces I-ORG
dropped O
the O
atomic O
bomb O
'' O
Little B-PRODUCT
Boy I-PRODUCT
'' O
on O
the O
city O
at O
about O
the O
height O
of O
Empire B-FAC
State I-FAC
Building I-FAC
. O

The O
casualties O
in O
such O
buildings O
near O
the O
centre O
of O
explosion O
were O
almost O
100% B-PERCENT
. O

The O
atomic O
explosion O
almost O
completely O
destroyed O
Hiroshima's B-GPE
identity O
as O
a O
city O
. O

Nearly O
everything O
was O
heavily O
damaged O
up O
to O
a O
radius O
of O
3 B-QUANTITY
miles I-QUANTITY
from O
the O
blast O
, O
and O
beyond O
this O
distance O
damage O
, O
although O
comparatively O
light O
, O
extended O
for O
several O
more O
miles O
. O

Glass O
was O
broken O
up O
to O
12 B-QUANTITY
miles I-QUANTITY
. O

Hiroshima B-WORK_OF_ART
is O
a O
1946 DATE
book PRODUCT
in O
English B-LANGUAGE
by O
American B-NORP
author O
John B-PERSON
Hersey I-PERSON
. O

New B-WORK_OF_ART
Yorker I-WORK_OF_ART
essayist O
Roger B-PERSON
Angell I-PERSON
wrote O
that O
its O
story O
became O
a O
part O
of O
our O
ceaseless O
thinking O
about O
world B-EVENT
wars I-EVENT
and O
nuclear O
holocaust O
. O

On O
October B-DATE
30, I-DATE 
2018 I-DATE
, O
the B-ORG
UN I-ORG
Human I-ORG
Rights I-ORG
Committee -ORG
adopted O
a O
new O
General B-LAW
comment I-LAW
No. I-LAW
36 I-LAW
on I-LAW
article I-LAW
6 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
International I-LAW
Covenant I-LAW
on I-LAW
Civil I-LAW
and I-LAW
Political I-LAW
Rights I-LAW
, O
on O
the O
right O
to O
life O
, O
which O
concludes O
that O
the O
threat O
or O
use O
of O
nuclear O
weapons O
is O
incompatible O
with O
the B-LAW
Right I-LAW
to I-LAW
Life I-LAW
and O
may O
amount O
to O
a O
crime O
under O
international B-LAW
law I-LAW
. O






